Quiet Mirza !
Mirza , quiet now .
Good afternoon , madame .
Yes , what is it ?
I 'm sorry to bother you .
I was told about an apartment .
This is the right building though , isn 't it ?
Who told you ?
A friend of mine .
Well , a relation , actually .
The door .
Sorry .
I gather it 's a small two-room apartment ?
Think that 's all I got to do ?
Some people think a concierge is a slave .
Not me , not me , I assure you .
Would it be more convenient if I came back later ?
Anyway , you have to speak with Monsieur Zy .
I can only show the apartment .
I don 't want to be a nuisance
but if it were at all possible .
And if I might offer you some small compensation
for your trouble , which is only reasonable .
What a lovely little doggie you are .
You 're Mirza , aren 't you ?
It 's a ...
It 's a nice name , Mirza .
I 'm sorry .
No .
The previous tenant threw herself out of the window .
You can still see where she fell .
Look .
He 's gonna have to fix that .
She 's not dead yet , though she might as well be .
She 's in the Bretonneau Hospital .
What if she gets better ?
Don 't worry , she won 't get better .
You know , you 're onto a good thing here .
Poor woman , what are the terms , do you know ?
Well , there 's a fee for the water .
All the plumbing is new .
You used to have to go out to the landing to get water .
- And the toilet ? - It 's right over there .
You just go around the corridor , and there it is .
That 's a view worth looking at .
How much is the premium ?
The rent is 600 francs a month .
The premium , I 'm not sure about .
I think he wants 5,000 francs .
Five thousand ?
That 's a lot of money .
It 's not my business .
For that , you 'll have to talk to Monsieur Zy .
He lives right down here .
I have to get back now .
All right , all right , we 're not deaf .
We don 't give to charity .
It 's about the apartment .
What apartment ?
On the floor above .
Could I speak to Monsieur Zy ?
Good afternoon .
Have you seen the apartment ?
Yes , that 's why I wanted to talk to you ,
to discuss the terms .
Five thousand premium , six hundred a month .
That 's a lot of money .
I couldn 't pay more than 4,000 .
The concierge told you about the water ?
Yes , she did .
It 's damned hard to find an apartment
these clays , you know .
There 's a student up on the sixth floor ,
gave me half that much for a single room .
Please , don 't get me wrong .
I 'm not trying to criticize your apartment
but the toilet is a problem .
Suppose I got sick , which I don 't often do ,
I can assure you of that .
And I had to relieve myself in the middle of the night .
It wouldn 't be very convenient , would it ?
On the other hand , I could pay you
the 4,000 right away , in cash .
It 's not only a question of the money .
Let 's be quite clear about that , Monsieur ...
Trelkovsky .
I won 't exactly starve without your 5,000 .
No , I 'm renting the apartment because it 's vacant .
And because I know they don 't grow on trees .
Of course , Monsieur Zy .
It 's perfectly reasonable , I understand your point .
Could I offer you a cigarette ?
You want 5,000 , fine .
But if you got paid by check , you 'd have to declare it .
Wouldn 't you rather get 4,000 in cash ?
I 'd rather get 5,000 in cash than 4,000 in cash .
It 's perfectly natural .
Anyway , the former tenant is not dead yet .
If she comes back , you won 't even get your 4,000 .
You get nothing .
Are you married ?
Excuse the question but it 's because of the children .
This is a very quiet building .
My wife and I are getting on now ...
I wouldn 't say that , Monsieur Zy .
I know what I 'm saying .
My wife and I are getting on .
We don 't like a lot of noise .
You needn 't worry , Monsieur Zy .
I am very quiet myself , and I am a bachelor .
Bachelors can be a problem too .
If you 're looking for a place
to entertain your girlfriends ,
I 'd rather take 2,000 and give it to somebody
who really needs it .
I quite agree , but I am not that type .
Well now , I can 't give you a definite answer
while Mademoiselle Choule is still alive .
But I like you .
You seem to be a serious young man to me .
I want to visit Mademoiselle Choule .
- Simone Choule ? - That 's right .
Are you a relative ?
I 'm a friend .
Can I help you ?
Are you the head nurse , ma 'am ?
- Yes . - I 'm very glad I found you .
Because I was told at the reception desk to see you first .
It 's about Mademoiselle Choule .
Bed 18 .
May I see her ?
She 's not to be disturbed .
She was in a coma till yesterday .
Go ahead , but don 't try to talk to her .
Well , he said he 'd come by Wednesday .
Are you a friend of hers ?
Excuse me .
I can 't believe it .
I just can 't believe it .
I was with her the night before .
No , two nights before .
She was in such good spirits .
Why ?
Why would she do a thing like that ?
To tell you the truth , I 'm not a close , I ...
I hardly know her at all , actually , but believe me
I 'm terribly upset about ...
- Yeah . - What 's happened .
It 's awful .
Simone ?
Simone .
You do recognize me , don 't you ?
It 's me , Stella .
Your friend , Stella .
Don 't you recognize me ?
You 'll have to leave now , your bag .
Is there any hope of saving her ?
What do you mean ?
If we can save her , we 'll save her .
Careful , you mustn 't give in to your grief .
If you like , we could go and have something to drink .
I think it would help you .
There is a ...
Here .
What would you like to drink ?
I don 't know .
I 'll have a beer , no , a coffee .
Coffee , and the lady ?
I don 't want a coffee .
You should have something strong , it will pick you up .
I 'll have a small glass of Beaujolais .
A small glass of Beaujolais and a Martini .
- No coffee ? - No , no , a Martini .
I completely forgot I have a phone call to make .
I 'll be right back .
Waiter !
All right , all right , I 'm coming .
I 'll never understand suicide .
I have no argument against it ,
but it 's beyond my comprehension .
Did you ever discuss it with her ?
Never .
I just can 't believe it .
It 's terrible , terrible .
It 's terrible , yeah .
Could it have been a disappointment in love , perhaps ?
Something like that ? - Who with ?
I don 't know , some man .
You know she wasn 't interested in men .
Yes , I know , but ...
Women as sensitive as she was ,
as she is , I mean , often tend to have
much more complicated relationships than they seem to ...
Perhaps she will pull out of it anyway .
I doubt it .
Did you notice that she didn 't even recognize me ?
A tragedy .
Hey , man , you got any bread for an artist ?
I don 't seem to have any change .
I don 't care , I 'll take what you got .
There , you see , I 've only got notes .
Come on , you don 't wanna look cheap
in front of your girlfriend .
Not , not a word of thanks , did you notice ?
I don 't like tramps .
You shouldn 't have given him anything .
Would you like to have a drink ?
No , thanks .
Right .
Goodbye , then .
- Goodbye . - Hope to see you soon .
What is it ?
Just came over from CNMA .
Was it sent by Monsieur Lott ?
Uh-huh , Monsieur Lott , right .
That must be the Villa LeDuc , then .
Yes , that 's right .
Yeah , that 's the Villa LeDuc .
Unmounted , Number 2601 .
" Make detailed copy of spire as indicated
" in the lower left-hand corner
" beside the registration number . "
You have to do it by next Thursday .
I 'm calling to ask you if you have any news
about Mademoiselle Simone Choule .
- What department is she in ? - Surgery .
- Choule , with a C ? - That 's right .
Simone Choule . - Are you a relative ?
No , I 'm a friend .
The patient died at 4 : 20 p.m. yesterday .
Thank you .
Good bye .
- Morning , monsieur . - Morning .
- Live opposite ? - Yes , I just moved in .
You rented the apartment of that girl
that jumped out of the window , huh ?
Yes sir , did you know her ?
Sure , I did , came in every morning .
Always sat in the same place .
Right there where you are now .
A cup of chocolate and a roll and butter .
Never drank coffee .
Used to say , " If I have a coffee ,
" I can 't sleep for two days . "
It 's a question of what you 're used to .
Shall I make you a chocolate ?
A question of temperament too , I think .
Still , a young girl like that killing herself .
I can 't imagine why .
No reason at all , probably .
A moment of depression , and wham , it 's all over .
Robert .
Do you sell cigarettes ?
Yes , what would you like ?
Gauloises Bleues , please .
I 'm right out of Gauloises .
What else do you have ?
Gitanes or Marlboro .
Mademoiselle Choule always smoked Marlboro .
Would you like a pack ?
No , no , thank you .
Simone Choule , the Lord has taken thee to his bosom .
Just as a shepherd brings in his sheep at the close of day .
What could be more natural , of greater consolation ?
Is it not the fondest hope and desire of all of us
that we shall one day rejoin the flock of holy ones ?
Hope of eternal life ?
The true life ?
Shorn of all worldly cares ?
Face to face in eternal blessedness with Almighty God
who through his son our Lord Jesus Christ
died for us on the cross .
Who deigns to look down upon us poor mortal creatures .
Full of love , infinitely merciful .
The sick , the suffering , the dying .
Yes , the dying ,
the icy tomb .
Thou shalt return to the dust from whence thou came .
And only thy bones remain .
The worms shall consume thy eyes .
Thy lips , thy mouth .
They shall enter into thy ears .
They shall enter into thy nostrils .
Thy body shall putrefy unto its innermost recesses .
And shall give off a noisome stench .
Yea , Christ is ascended into heaven
and hath joined the host of angels on high ,
but not for creeps like you .
Full of the basest vice .
Yearning only for carnal satisfaction .
How dare you pester me , and mock at me to my very face .
What audacity !
What are you doing here in my temple ?
The graveyard is where you belong .
Thou shalt stink .
Thou shalt stink like some putrefied corpse
lying along the wayside .
Verily I say unto thee ,
thou shalt never enter into my kingdom .
Four , three , two , one , zero !
Our hero , there he is .
Hey , Trelkovsky , the lucky lodger , huh ?
Lucille Pampin , from Nice . - On the Riviera .
She 's 5 '4 " and 140 pounds .
Best blow job in Paris !
- Very pleased to meet you . - How do you do ?
Don 't anybody get up .
What is this , no more chairs than that ?
What a dump ! - There is a table right here .
Well look , your fiancé can come and sit on my knees , okay ?
Come on .
It 's against my principles , you know ?
Hey , come on now , give me a hand .
- Hi , how are you ? - Wait a second .
- Grab that end , will you ? - That 's more like it .
Careful , huh ?
Put it right in the middle there .
That 's it , much nicer now .
What do we do with chairs , though ?
Well , maybe , there 's a bed here , let 's use that .
- Yeah , why not , come on . - Move that table over .
Okay , yeah .
Take the table outta there first .
Hold it will you ?
- Want me to do anything ? - Thank you , you 're very kind .
Here , let me finish that .
We 'll just get this salad finished .
Have you met Viviane ?
Hello .
Hurry up , a waste of time .
There , set her down . - There , that 's okay .
Easy does it .
What the hell is this ?
Is that one of yours ?
No , no , cut it out , he 's got a heart of gold .
How about you ?
That 's right , he 's got the heart of a chick .
Sure , you would , you 'd be happy to do it
for a little bread .
No , I wouldn 't , I 'm not interested .
You could offer me a fortune
and I still wouldn 't dream of it .
Who you trying to kid ?
You think there 's anyone dumb enough to offer you a fortune ?
She 's talking about the principle , you jerk .
- The principle ? - That 's right .
You know what I think of your principles ?
You wanna know what I think ?
Well , come on , what do you think ?
Well , it 's a lot of crap , that 's what your principles are .
I tell you , I 'd do it for nothing .
- You would ? - You bet I would .
Absolutely nothin ' .
It takes all kinds .
Right , nobody wants me to , but I 'd pay them to let me .
I 'd write a check , but I wouldn 't pay .
I saw one once , it makes you wanna throw up .
Would anybody mind if the subject were changed ?
What do you want to talk about then ,
women 's lib , social security ?
Keep women 's lib out of it , for Christ 's sake .
Yeah listen , have you looked at ' em ?
Have you looked at those militants ?
It 's enough to turn you queer .
Look what that pig 's doing now .
He 's actually pissing in the sink , how revolting !
Come on , get off my back , will ya ?
It 's not my fault if there 's no John
in this crummy apartment .
Huh ?
Monsieur ?
You 're making a great deal of noise , monsieur .
It 's after one o 'clock ,
and you 're making a great deal of noise .
I 'm just having a few friends over for a quiet chat .
Quiet ?
I live upstairs ,
and I can hear every word you 're saying .
You 've been dragging furniture around ,
stamping about the place .
It 's intolerable .
Do you intend to carry on like this much longer ?
Who is that asshole ?
Look .
I 'm terribly sorry I woke you .
I will be more careful from now on .
You don 't seem to give a damn about anyone else .
It 's all very well to have a good time .
But some people have to work , you know ?
Tomorrow 's Sunday , and it 's reasonable
for me to have a few people around on Saturday evening .
No , monsieur .
It 's not reasonable to make such a racket ,
even on a Saturday evening !
We will be more careful .
Good night , monsieur .
Sure , soon you won 't even be able to jerk off
without him knocking on the door .
Idiot .
You shouldn 't let him push you around that way .
No , you should counterattack .
You know what ?
We gotta take revenge .
Sure , why don 't we set the joint on fire ?
We could stuff scorpions down his chimney .
- Or crabs . - No , no , crabs won 't work .
Scorpions . - No , we 'll drill a hole
in the wall and force gas into it .
We 'll make a hole in the floor .
Or make a hole in the floor .
No , don 't be so silly .
You 're such a moron . - That 's because he only
thinks below the belt . - What 's this ?
Well , I 'll be damned , he 's throwing us out of the house .
- Look , it 's late . - Come on .
Okay , gang , let 's go find some place else .
- Give me my coat . - Let 's go , everybody out .
Somebody pass me my coat , huh ?
Be careful .
Be careful with those coats . - Come on , on your feet .
- My shoes . - Let 's go , everybody out .
- We going or what ? - Sure , buddy .
- Bye , everybody . - Good bye .
- Come on , everyone . - Night !
Let 's go , everybody out !
One hell of a party .
Good night , my friend , bye !
Hey !
Don 't make so much noise , people are sleeping !
Good morning , Monsieur Zy .
Lovely day , isn 't it ?
I 'm terribly embarrassed about last night .
And I can promise you it will never happen again .
I should hope not .
You woke up both me and my wife .
We couldn 't get back to sleep all night .
What was the meaning of all that ?
I thought I 'd have a few friends over
to celebrate my good fortune
of having found his lovely apartment .
A sort of a house warming ,
without disturbing anyone .
And then , you know how it is with the best will in the world
and not dreaming of disturbing anyone .
You talk , you 're having a good time .
And before you even know it , you 're making so much noise .
But , I 'm sorry .
I can promise you it 'll never happen again .
Well , I 'm very glad to hear that , Monsieur Trelkovsky .
Because I was seriously thinking of taking steps .
Apartments are hard enough to come by these clays .
So it 's worth keeping the one you have , don 't you think ?
" Outraged neighbor shoots tipsy tenor
" for singing La Tosca at 3 : 00 a.m.
" Louis Marais , age 39 , a bachelor and traveling salesman ,
" came home at 3 : 00 in the morning after one drink too many .
" And proceeded to sing opera with his windows wide open .
" When a neighbor , Monsieur Pierrot , expressed a wish
" that he put off his warbling until somewhat later ,
" Monsieur Marais promptly illustrated his contempt
" for such a suggestion with an air from Tosca
" delivered on the hall landing .
" Monsieur Pierrot reappeared with a gun
" and emptied it into the poor tenor
" who died before the ambulance reached the hospital .
" The murderer is under arrest . "
You there ,
quiet down !
How much longer are you gonna keep up this racket ?
Who is it ?
It 's me .
What can I do for you ?
Monsieur , was it you who registered the complaint ?
A complaint ?
Against whom ?
Against me for causing the disturbance at night .
I never made any complaint .
Someone has registered a complaint .
It came this morning .
She is the one who makes all the noise all night long .
- Who ? - That old woman .
She 's evil .
She 's done everything she could to make things
difficult for us .
Just because the girl is disabled .
You didn 't register a complaint ?
Of course not .
Then it must have been her .
I asked downstairs , they said it might have been you .
Monsieur , we go to bed early , not like her .
She can 't sleep at night ,
so she walks up and down her apartment ,
moves the furniture around .
She keeps me and my daughter awake .
Do you know what she did , monsieur ?
Jammed a broom up against my door .
I had to heave it open with all my strength .
I twisted a muscle in my shoulder
and now she wants to have us thrown out .
She can 't have you thrown out .
- Can 't she ? - Of course not .
I never make any noise , monsieur , honestly .
Well even if you did , they can 't throw you out like that .
Nonsense . - Are you sure ?
Absolutely .
God bless you .
God bless you , monsieur , thank you .
What about your neighbors ?
I 'm getting used to them .
A question of habit , you know .
They have to get used to me too , you know .
If they keep bugging you , Simon and I know a few ways
of dealing with them , eh , Simon ?
Sure , we know some great tricks .
Like we could come around in the middle of the night
and yell up at you from the courtyard , you see what I mean ?
Hey , Trelkovsky ! Come out for a drink !
Come on now , get movin ' !
Or we could knock on the floor below
after midnight , of course .
That 's right , knock on the door shouting ,
" On your feet , shitface , we 're off to the park
" for a blow job ! "
You know
There 's something odd going on in my building .
I quite often see people in the toilets ,
on the other side of the courtyard .
What are you , a Peeping Tom now ?
Do you mean people together in the shit house ?
Like an orgy ?
No , no , they just stand there for hours , you know ?
Absolutely dead still .
They 're obviously playing with themselves .
Not at all .
He just told you they stand dead still .
Can you play with yourself without moving ?
What would you like to drink ?
What are you having ?
- Beer . - Beer 's fine .
What 's the matter ?
Nothing , just ...
Don 't worry , I know what I 'm doin ' .
- Turn it down a little . - Leave it alone .
They 're used to it by now .
But it 's too loud , even for us .
Try and get used to it .
Try to enjoy it , while you can .
You can 't do it at home .
Neighbor ?
I hope so .
Sorry to bother you , monsieur , I see you 've company .
But I wonder , could you turn down the sound a little ?
My wife 's sick .
So she 's sick , is she ?
Well what am I supposed to do about it ?
Stop living because of her ?
If she 's sick , why doesn 't she go to a hospital ?
I 'll play my records when I want and as loud as I want !
You know , I 'm a bit hard of hearing myself
but that 's no reason to be deprived of my music .
And don 't try anything funny .
I know the Superintendent of Police .
See , that 's how you deal with them .
What if his wife really is ...
So what ?
I don 't go moaning to him every time I don 't feel well .
He won 't come back either , I can promise you that .
Just a moment please .
Who is it ?
Isn 't this Simone Choule 's apartment ?
Yes ,
well it used to be , I 'm the new tenant .
Has she moved then ?
Come in , please , don 't stand there like that .
Nothing 's happened to her , I hope .
Please sit down , Monsieur ...
Badar .
Pleased to meet you , Monsieur Badar ,
my name is Trelkovsky .
I 'm afraid there 's been an unfortunate ...
Did you know her well ?
Did I know her ?
She committed suicide .
She threw herself out of the window .
If you 'd like to see . - But ...
But Why ?
Why would she do a thing like that ?
No one seems to know .
Do you know Stella ? - No .
She doesn 't know either .
No one knows why she did it .
I went back to the Egyptian department
at the Louvre this morning .
I found a nice postcard and I sent it to her .
What irony .
Years of affection without ever daring to say anything .
I acted as though we were just friends each time I saw her ,
which wasn 't very often I can tell you that .
It just isn 't fair .
The day I summon up enough courage to tell her ,
I find out ...
I find out she 's ...
Why ?
Why didn 't I ever tell her ?
She 's gone , without ever knowing it .
We 'll be closing now ,
Monsieur Trelkovsky . - Yeah .
Life isn 't worth living anymore .
- You mustn 't . - That 'll be six francs sixty .
You mustn 't think like that .
You 're young , you 'll forget .
Wait , wait .
Wait a minute .
Thank you .
I can promise you she didn 't suffer .
And she didn 't say anything ?
You sure ? - Absolutely certain .
All right , all right !
It 's my round , for Christ sakes !
Drinks for everyone .
Everyone except him .
Don 't mind him , he 's drunk .
Drunk .
What you 've done for me , it 's ...
It 's natural .
- It 's not natural . - It is natural .
- It 's not natural at all . - Natural .
Not many guys around like you .
It 's as simple as this .
You saved my life .
- Morning ! - Good morning .
Cup of chocolate , Monsieur Trelkovsky ?
Why not ?
Could I have some Gauloises Bleues , please ?
Yes .
I want some Gauloises , Gauloises Bleues .
I 'm sorry , I thought you said Marlboro .
I 've run out of Gauloises .
Robert will be here soon .
I 'll send him out for some .
Don 't bother , I 'll take the Marlboro 's .
Yes , I know !
I know I 'm making a noise .
You didn 't knock before when the thieves were here !
Perhaps they did knock before , mind you .
This can 't go on any longer , Monsieur Trelkovsky .
You kept everyone awake again .
All the neighbors are complaining .
I beg your pardon , Monsieur Zy ,
are you talking about last night ?
Of course I 'm talking about last night !
You made a fiendish racket .
I thought I 'd made it clear that you wouldn 't be staying
in my house much longer
if you went on behaving like that .
I 'm afraid I shall be forced to take steps .
I 've been robbed , Monsieur Zy !
I 'm on my way to the police station .
What do you mean ?
My house is a respectable place .
If you 're trying to get out of this
by making up some nonsense ... - It 's true !
My television 's gone , my camera , one of my suitcases .
I see .
Well , I 'm very sorry for you
but why are you going to the police ?
To tell them what happened .
Now look , Monsieur Trelkovsky ,
this is an honest house .
My tenants are honest people .
There 's no question of it .
No , no , let me finish .
You know how careful I am in choosing my tenants .
I let you have the apartment because I thought
you were an honest man .
Otherwise you could have offered me a million francs
and I 'd have laughed in your face .
Now if you go to the police ,
they 'll come ' round here asking all sorts of questions .
Useless questions of course ,
but all that can have a disastrous effect
on our reputation here .
I 'm saying this for your sake too .
For my sake ?
Well what have I done ?
Once anyone gets involved with the police ,
they 're always looked on with suspicion .
Especially if they 're not French .
But , I 'm a French citizen .
I know you 've clone nothing wrong ,
but other people won 't know that .
They 'll suspect you of , God knows what .
No , believe me , I know what I 'm talking about .
I know the Superintendent of Police here .
I 'll have a word with him about all this .
He 'll know what to do .
And by the way :
the former tenant always wore slippers after ten o 'clock .
It was much more comfortable for her .
And for the neighbors .
A pack of Marlboro .
Gimme a pack of Gauloises , will ya ?
A pack of Marlboro , please .
- A pack of Gauloises . - Six franc sixty .
Okay , see ya next week .
Hello , how are you ?
Very well , thanks .
I was just going to buy some cigarettes .
Come and join us .
These are some friends of mine .
- May I ? - Of course .
- Hi . - Hi .
Hi .
We were just talking about Simone .
- Simone ? - Simone Choule .
This is the guy I was telling you about .
The one I met at the hospital .
We were the last to see her alive .
Stella told us .
Simone didn 't seem to know her .
I don 't think she did .
- And you ? - Me ?
She didn 't recognize you either ?
It 's hard to say .
I couldn 't be sure one way or the other .
Perhaps she was trying to say something
when she screamed like that ?
Anyway , it 's the impression I get when I think back on it .
She was looking at you when she let out that cry .
You think so ?
You know , I still have some things of hers at home .
It 's depressing . - What 've you got of hers ?
I have some books , a couple of records .
There 's one of Simone 's books .
- I haven 't read it . - Nor have I.
I 'm not interested in Egyptology .
She left it behind one evening .
You can have it if you like .
You 're very kind , I would love to read it .
It 's a magnificent place you 've got here .
Better than where I live , I can tell you .
Sorry , if you don 't mind me asking ,
is the rent very high ?
I don 't pay for it .
It belongs to my brother .
He 's gone off to Peru , for a few months .
A year , traveling .
Look , this track .
Do you have any trouble with your neighbors ?
What sort of trouble ?
Well you know ,
these clays , relationships with neighbors
can get quite complicated , no ?
Little things that get blown up out of all proportion .
Know what I mean ?
No ,
no , I don 't .
I mind my own business .
So , so do I , it 's the best way .
If you like , I 'll take you home .
Should we go back to your place ?
- My place ? - Mm-hmm .
Okay ?
Sure , fine .
Only my place is a bit .
Well , it 's a bit difficult .
In fact it 's impossible .
Why ?
Have you got a girlfriend ?
Not exactly .
It 's just that I 've been repainting
and the place is in chaos ,
chaos .
We could still spend a couple of hours there .
On top of that ,
my uncle is just up from the country .
Staying a few days .
Well , how about your place ?
Take off your coat .
I 'll be right back .
I 'd love something to drink .
Cheers .
Why don 't you take your tie off ?
You look like you 're choking to death .
I found a tooth in my apartment .
It was in the hole . - A tooth ?
In a hole ?
Yeah .
A hole in the wall .
Wrapped in cotton wool .
So ?
No need to pull such a long face over a tooth .
Pretty weird though , isn 't it ?
Not really .
When I was young , we did it all the time .
Whenever one of my teeth fell out ,
I used to hide it .
My mother said it would turn into a coin .
Coin .
Oh , God .
Stella , I was wondering ...
Yeah ?
Tooth ...
A tooth is a part of ourselves , isn 't it ?
Like a bit of our personality .
I don 't know what you mean .
I remember in , in the newspaper .
A man lost his arm in an accident
and wanted to have it buried .
He wanted to do what ?
Have it buried in the cemetery .
He must have been nuts .
The authorities refused .
The arm was cremated and that was that .
Where did this happen , in France ?
I wonder if they refused to give him the ashes .
And if so , by what right ?
Haven 't you got anything more cheerful to talk about ?
All right , that 'll do .
Don 't worry .
Tell me ,
at what precise moment
does an individual stop being who he thinks he is ?
You know , I don 't like complications .
Cut off my arm , right ?
I say me and my arm .
You cut off my other arm ,
I say me and my two arms .
Take off ...
Take out my stomach ,
my kidneys ,
assuming that were possible ,
and I say me and my intestines ,
intestines ,
follow me ?
And now , if you cut off my head ,
would I say ,
me and my ,
me and my head , or me and my body ?
What right has my head to call itself me ?
What right ?
Oh , God .
Monsieur Trelkovsky ?
Stay , stay , Mirza , stay !
You were out all night , huh ?
Yes I ...
I had to stay with my uncle , he isn 't well .
I 'll tell Madame Dioz you 're back .
Madame Dioz ?
Who 's Madame Dioz ?
This isn 't for me !
Look !
" Best wishes from the Louvre ,
" Georges Badar . "
I should like to have a word with you , monsieur .
Please come in , madame .
I am Madame Dioz .
I 'm very pleased to meet you .
This is why I 've come to see you .
Please read it .
It is a petition , against the unspeakable Madame Gaderian .
She 's gone a little too far this time .
And we 've got to do something about it .
Look , even Monsieur Zy has signed , there .
Who is this Madame Gaderian ?
I don 't know her .
What do you mean you don 't know her ?
Who do you think makes all that dreadful noise ?
It is her , my clear young man , it is her .
Do you know what she does ?
She does her washing up in the middle of the night .
And she whistles at the same time .
Now , does a civilized person behave like that ?
No , I suppose not .
Well go on then , sign .
It 's simply a question of solidarity .
She 's making life impossible for ...
For the other tenants .
Is she the one who lives with a disabled daughter ?
Disabled ?
No , she has a boy .
A horrible , noisy brat who 's always playing skittles
or God knows what in the corridor .
Are you sure ?
I mean , are you absolutely certain
she doesn 't have a young daughter .
I don 't know what goes on in their lair .
Ask the concierge .
I 'm sorry , I 'm not signing any petition .
This woman has never bothered me .
I 've never seen her or even heard of her .
What apartment does she live in anyway ?
I shall make a note of your attitude .
I can see what we 're dealing with here .
Everyone for himself and never mind anyone else ?
Not at all , I ...
I know your type exactly , like that man opposite .
Right up until the day he was struck down with paralysis ,
then his neighbors let him stew in his own juice .
By all means do whatever you think best .
But I warn you ,
don 't come whining to me later .
Bastards !
What do they want me to do , drop dead ?
My wife is always saying that .
It 's for me .
It 's no use playing innocent with me .
I 've heard a good deal about you ,
Monsieur Trelkovsky , a good deal .
You specialize in breaches of the peace at night .
I 'm quite amazed , Inspector .
No one has said anything to me .
I 'm certainly not in the habit of making noise .
I have very few friends and I never entertain .
I 'm not interested in your stories .
I have a few other things to do as you may be aware .
However , I keep receiving complaints
and it 's my duty to see law and order are maintained .
So I say it once and for all ,
stop whatever it is you 're doing at night .
Trelkovsky , is that a Russian name ?
Polish , Polish .
So you 're not French ?
I 'm a French citizen .
Let me see your identity card .
It 's in a very poor state .
But you haven 't registered your change of address .
15 Rue Sedan , where is this ?
I 'm terribly sorry , I 'll do it at once .
You 'd be well advised to .
Right , this time I shall close my eyes
to the whole business .
Just make sure I don 't hear any more about you .
I won 't have some little troublemaker disturbing the peace .
Thank you very much , Inspector .
Good-bye .
Good afternoon , madame .
I would like to know who registered a complaint against me .
Do you know who it was ?
If you didn 't make so much noise ,
there wouldn 't be any complaints .
Was there a petition ?
Was it that woman that came to see me
the other clay , Madame Dioz ?
You only have yourself to blame .
Did you sign it ?
That 's it , she 's won .
They 've all signed it .
All except you , monsieur .
I 've come to thank you , you 're a good person .
I don 't like to get mixed up in this kind of thing .
Nonsense , no , you are a good person .
I can see it in your eyes .
I got even with them .
And the concierge too , she 's as bad as all of them .
I paid them back all right .
They gave me the idea .
Do you know what I did ?
I did it on the staircase in front of everyone 's door .
It 's their own fault .
They gave me the idea .
I didn 't do it by your door .
I don 't want to cause you any trouble .
- How long ago ? - Just now .
I would love to see their faces when they find out .
It serves them right , all of them .
But they 'll say I did it !
Good night , monsieur , sleep well .
Hey , look .
They 'll drive me to suicide .
All right ,
I 'll show them .
Gorgeous shoes .
Simply , where in the world did you find them ?
If it wasn 't
Eighty francs , you 're kidding .
Supermarket , yes .
She 's not as young as she thinks she is .
Beautiful ,
beautiful .
Adorable .
A goddess , divine ,
divine .
I think I 'm pregnant .
Monsters !
They 'll never turn me into Simone Choule .
Never !
Monsieur Trelkovsky .
Do you remember the conditions on which I let you
have this apartment ?
I most certainly do , Monsieur Zy .
May I know what you 're referring to ?
I 'm referring to what I said about women .
Yes , of course .
Then why do you bring them around here ?
What ?
I never brought any women around here .
I know what I 'm talking about .
You had a woman up in your room .
You can 't deny it .
I 'll turn a blind eye to it this time .
But this is the last time .
I hope that 's clear .
Good morning , Monsieur Trelkovsky .
Bring me a coffee .
You don 't want a chocolate ?
No , I just told you , I want a coffee .
But you always have a chocolate .
You always serve me without asking what I want .
Now , today I am telling you , I 'd like a coffee .
I 'm sorry , but the problem is , you see
the machine 's broken down .
Your sure you won 't have a chocolate ?
No , why the hell should I ?
It 's nothing to get sore about .
I 'll have a glass of red wine .
I suppose you 're out of Gauloises .
That 's right , we 've only got Marlboros .
You can keep them .
I know just what you are up to .
Goddamn murderers !
No good looking at me like that .
I know exactly what your little scheme is .
What 's wrong ?
My boat .
- Which one ? - The red one .
- What 's your name ? - Patrick .
- Patrick ! - Patrick .
And you 've lost your boat , the red one ?
Okay , I 'll get it back for you .
Filthy little brat !
Please , hello .
Please .
What are you doing to me ?
It 's him , he 's there !
I 'll fight .
I 'll fight to the bitter end .
Who is it ?
It 's me , Trelkovsky .
Were you sleeping ?
What 's the matter ?
Sorry to bother you at this hour of the morning .
Do you mind if I stayed here for a while ?
You 're strange .
You must tell me .
I wouldn 't mind , really .
No , no , of course you can stay .
Look , you 're hurt .
It 's nothing , really .
But it 's filthy .
That 's nothing .
Wait , wait , I think I 've got some ...
Some things here .
How did you do that ?
It 's them .
' Who ?
They 're trying to kill me .
Drive me to suicide .
What are you talking about ?
Who 's trying to kill you ?
Stella , I 've been lying to you .
I 'm living in her apartment .
Whose apartment ?
Simone 's .
I rented Simone Choule 's apartment .
How did you rent it ?
She 's dead because of the neighbors .
It was a plot .
A plot against Simone ?
You 're completely insane .
I 'm not insane , listen .
They forced her to commit suicide .
I can prove it .
And they are trying to do the same thing to me .
Everything 's ready .
They worked it all out , every detail .
Do you know what they 've been doing to me ?
It 's ...
It 's so appalling ...
So incredible that I can hardly tell you yet .
It 's true , I swear it .
Oh , tell me , tell me , I 'm listening .
They 've been trying to turn me into Simone Choule .
There now , I 'm your friend .
I 'm going to help you .
- Come now . - To turn me
into Simone Choule ! - You 're exhausted , lie down .
I 'm going to leave Paris in a couple of clays .
They 'll never find me .
You 're right , yes , that 's the best thing to do .
You 're the only one I can trust , aren 't you ?
It 's me , Stella ,
don 't be frightened .
You do recognize me , don 't you ?
Sorry , I was having a nightmare .
I must get to work now , I 'm late .
I 'll be back around 8 : 00 .
I 've left your breakfast ready .
I love you .
And I love you .
I even went out and bought you some croissants .
Please stay with me , don 't leave me alone .
Now , listen , I 'm late .
If you want to go out , just leave the keys under the mat .
I 'll get another pair made tomorrow .
We 'll each have our own set then .
- Please don 't go . - Don 't be naughty now .
You 're to be good and stay here .
You 've got everything you need .
If you like , you can go out and get some fresh air .
I 'll bring some food back this evening .
We 'll eat in , or go out to a restaurant ,
if you like .
We 'll see how you feel .
See you tonight then .
Is anyone there ?
Filthy bitch !
They 're all in it together .
They 're all in it together !
Stop here , stop , stop .
Hey , what 's wrong ?
Nothing , I 'm getting out .
- Is that all right ? - Yeah .
Thank you , monsieur .
Thank you very much .
Have you got any idea where I can buy a gun ?
I 'll pay good money .
Get the hell out of here , you little punk !
Hey , he wants to buy a gun , this bugger .
What ?
I 'll tell the cops , you little shit !
I told you not to drive so fast .
Now look what 's happened .
Monsieur , are you hurt ?
People who can 't drive should take taxis , you old jerks .
How dare you say that !
My wife hasn 't had an accident in 25 years .
He 's right .
The guy walked right under the wheels .
I saw the whole thing .
Let me through , please .
Excuse me , let me through .
Let me through .
Excuse me , excuse me , I 'm a doctor .
Murderers .
Believe me , my wife and I are terribly upset
about what has happened .
Please stand back .
On the curb , back .
Officer , this is how it happened .
Your ID , please .
Yours too , monsieur .
You 're very lucky .
Only a few scratches .
Nothing broken .
But you should have an X-ray .
It 's nothing serious .
In my opinion it 's a mild case of delirium tremens .
The driver and her husband made a statement
and they 've offered to drive him home .
Do you think that 's all right , doctor ?
Or should I call for an ambulance ?
Well , if this gentleman can manage it , it 'd be fine .
We 'd be glad to give this poor man a lift home , of course .
We 'll take you home , huh ?
That is preposterous !
No , please !
They were trying to kill me , yeah ?
They were playing football with a human head .
I 'll give him a shot of something to calm him down .
No , no injection ,
I don 't want any injection .
I don 't want ...
I don 't want an injection .
They tried ...
They tried to kill me .
Mirza , quiet down !
Good evening , madam .
This gentleman has had a slight accident .
Nothing serious , though .
Nothing to worry about , but ...
What did he do now ?
I think we better get him up to his apartment .
How did it happen ?
He sort of jumped out in front of the car , and ...
Luckily my wife has very good reflexes .
What 's going on here ?
It 's him again .
That bastard !
Stay , stay Mirza , stay .
- What was that ? - Down in the courtyard .
We 'd better call an ambulance .
Go get one , quick .
You shouldn 't move !
Monsieur , I swear I am not Simone Choule .
- Quick , get him a blanket . - It 's murder .
Two suicides in succession .
It 's quite unbelievable .
Look how he 's dressed .
He must be insane .
And we just finished repairing the roof .
I knew there was something wrong with him
the first time I saw him .
Oh , God , Monsieur Trelkovsky !
Be reasonable , wait for the ambulance .
You gang of killers !
I 'll show you some blood .
You wanted a clean death , didn 't you ?
- Be reasonable . - It 's going to be dirty .
Unforgettable .
It was better last time , wasn 't it ?
Well , I 'm not Simone Choule ,
I 'm Trelkovsky !
Trelkovsky !
All right , all right , what 's going on ?
A tenant jumped out
of a window . - Again ?
You must be getting them wholesale .
Where is he now ?
He 's gone back up to his apartment .
I think he must have had some kind of a brainstorm .
He 's gonna jump again !
He 's not going to do it again , is he ?
Take it easy , don 't move !
We 'll come up and get you , okay ?
Be reasonable now .
Please , it 's enough .
Why is this happening ?
Oh , God , no .
Monsieur Trelkovsky , don 't do anything silly !
Are you a friend of hers ?
Oh , I 'm sorry .
What on earth could have happened ?
Why would she do a thing like that ?
To tell you the truth ,
I 'm not a friend of hers at all .
I hardly know her , actually , but ...
Simone .
You do recognize me , don 't you ?
It 's me ,
Stella .
Your friend , Stella .
Don 't you recognize me ?